Guide to the Emmons Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
George Thornton Emmons's printed articles are arranged chronologically at the end of Series VI. He has inserted notes, correspondence, extra illustrations, and other material into his copies of "The Basketry of the Tlingit," "Extract from the New York Times," and "Tahltan Indians."
Series VII, Family Papers, consists primarily of artwork by George Foster Emmons, George Thornton Emmons, and his wife Kittie M. Emmons.
There are more extensive papers in Series VII for George Foster Emmons. Emmons's compiled a scrapbook of newspaper clippings regarding the land battles of the Civil War. One of the earliest documents for Emmons is a volume on "Seamanship," a combination of notes and sketches, which he composed after finishing his training at the Brooklyn naval school. A scrapbook of invitations for 1869-73 gives evidence of his social position toward the end of his career. Finally, the collection includes drawings he made while serving on the frigate Brandywine.
George Thornton Emmons, like his father, was an artist. His "Christmas Pamphlet" for 1886 contains a series of oil paintings depicting Alaskan scenery. The only other material related to George Thornton Emmons are two diplomas noting his involvement with a 1909 "Alaskan-Yukon-Pacific Exposition." The collection also holds a watercolor by Kittie Emmons.
Chilkat Indians; Courts-martial and courts of inquiry -- United States; Desertion, Naval -- United States; Indians of North America -- Alaska; Indians of North America -- Northwest, Pacific; Navy spouses; Tahltan Indians; Tlingit Indians; Warships -- United States; Alaska -- History -- 1867-1959; Canada -- Boundaries -- United States; United States -- Boundaries -- Canada; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Blockades; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Naval operations; Drawings; Photoprints; Ships' logs; Seamen -- United States; Ammen, Daniel, 1820-1898; Emmons, Antonia; Emmons, F. W.; Emmons, George F. (George Foster), 1811-1884; Emmons, George Thornton; FitzGerald, Edward; Hambleton, Samuel, 1777-1851; Jenkins, Thornton A. (Thornton Alexander), 1811-1893; Marchand, John B., b. 1808; Mercer, Samuel, d. 1862; Sawyer, H. B.; Thorton, Francis Anthony; Welles, Gideon, 1802-1878; Emmons family; Thornton family; United States. Navy ( History Civil War, 1861-1865); United States. Navy ( Officers); United States. Navy. North Pacific Squadron; United States. Navy. West Gulf Squadron; Boston (Ship); Brandywine (Ship); Lackawanna (Ship); Ossipee (Ship); Savannah (Ship)
- G. F. Emmons Personal Correspondence, 1828-81; Series I; 2.75; (7 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, G. F. Emmons Personal Correspondence, housed in Boxes 1-7, contains letters to Emmons, which he arranged into bound letterbooks and labeled "Personal-Official." This organization has been preserved.
  - 1828-51 LETTERS FROM SHIPMATES, OFFICERS, & FAMILY
    - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
    - Description of letters by George Thornton Emmons, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Letters, 1828-29 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Letters, 1833-37 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Letters, 1842-52 (Box 1, Folder 8-19)
  - 1851-56 PERSONAL & OFFICIAL
    - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21-23)
    - Letters, 1851-52 (Box 1, Folder 24-30)
    - Letters, 1853 Jan-May (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
    - Letters, 1853 Jul-Dec (Box 2, Folder 33-34)
    - Letters, 1854-56 (Box 2, Folder 35-39)
  - 1856-59 PERSONAL LETTERS FROM RELATIVES & OTHERS
    - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 41-43)
    - Letters, 1856-57 (Box 2, Folder 44-51)
    - Letters, 1858 Jan-Sep (Box 2, Folder 52-53)
    - Letters, 1858 Oct-Dec (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Letters, 1855-60 (Box 3, Folder 55-59)
  - 1860-62 PERSONAL LETTERS & OFFICIAL
    - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 61-63)
    - Letters, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 64-65)
    - Letters, 1861 Jan-Jul (Box 3, Folder 66-70)
    - Letters, 181 Aug-Dec (Box 4, Folder 71-73)
    - Letters, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 74-75)
  - 1863-65 OFFICIAL & PERSONAL, CIVIL WAR
    - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 77-79)
    - Letters, 1862-63 (Box 4, Folder 80-87)
    - Letters, 1864-65 (Box 5, Folder 88-96)
  - 1865-70 PERSONAL & SOME FAMILY
    - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 98-100)
    - Letters, 1865-67 (Box 5, Folder 101-106)
    - Letters, 1868-70 (Box 6, Folder 107-115)
    - Letters, 1881 (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - 1870-71 OFFICIAL & PERSONAL
    - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 118-20)
    - Miscellaneous material, inside front cover, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Letters, 1870-71 (Box 6, Folder 122-25)
    - Letters, 1871 Feb (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - Letters, 1871 Mar-Dec (Box 7, Folder 127-35)
- G. F. Emmons Offical Correspondence, 1856-76; Series II; 2; (5 boxes)
  Series II, G. F. Emmons Offical Correspondence, housed in Boxes 8-12, contains letters to Emmons, which he arranged into letterbooks and labeled "Official." This organization has been preserved.
  - 1828-50 [OFFICIAL LETTERS]
    See: Manuscript 168, Yale Collection of Western Americana
  - 1850-63 OFFICIAL LETTERS
    - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 137-39)
    - Letters, 1856-60 (Box 8, Folder 140-46)
  - 1862-1864 OFFICIAL
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 147-49)
    - Miscellaneous material, inside front cover, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 150)
    - Letters, 1861-63 (Box 8, Folder 151-55)
    - "Specifications for Building a Revenue Cutter", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 156)
  - 1862-1865 OFFICIAL, CIVIL WAR
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 157-59)
    - Miscellaneous material, inside front cover, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 160)
    - Letters, 1862 (Box 8, Folder 161)
    - Letters, 1863-65 (Box 9, Folder 162-73)
  - 1865-68 OFFICIAL LETTERS
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 174-76)
    - "Directions for Taking Deep Sea Soundings", 1850 May 1 (Box 9, Folder 177)
    - Letters, 1861 (Box 9, Folder 178)
    - Letters, 1862-66 (Box 10, Folder 179-88)
    - Letters, 1868-70 (Box 10, Folder 189-93)
  - 1866-68 OFFICIAL LETTERS
    - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 194)
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 195-97)
    - Letters, 1866-68 (Box 11, Folder 198-213)
    - Index (Box 12, Folder 214)
    - Newspaper clippings and miscellaneous papers, 1864, 1867, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 215)
  - [1872] OFFICIAL
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 216-18)
    - Index (Box 12, Folder 219)
    - Letters, 1872 (Box 12, Folder 220-29)
    - Sunday Dispatch: Philadelphia newspaper, vol. XXVIII, no. 42, 1876 January 23
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 542
- Additional Correspondence, G. F. Emmons, 1821-73; Series III; 0.25; (1 box)
  Series III, Additional Correspondence, G. F. Emmons, housed in Box 13, contains letters to Emmons, which were removed from letterbooks. The letters are arranged chronologically and some have been separated into subject groupings.
  - 1841-1873 LETTERS
    - Letters, 1821 (Box 13, Folder 230)
    - Letters, 1844-48 (Box 13, Folder 231-34)
    - "South Fork of the American River, California:" map
      See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 545
    - Letters, 1849-50 (Box 13, Folder 235-36)
    - [Report to the Senate Committee on the U.S. Navy], ca. 1850 (Box 13, Folder 237)
    - Letters, 1851-54 (Box 13, Folder 238-39)
    - Letters, 1871-73 (Box 13, Folder 240-41)
  - 1849-1850 LETTERS REGARDING COURT MARTIALS
    - Letters, 1848-50 (Box 13, Folder 242)
  - 1850 LETTERS REGARDING CALIFORNIA REAL ESTATE
    - Letters, 1850-51 (Box 13, Folder 243-44)
    - Letters, 1852-68 (Box 13, Folder 245)
- Family Correspondence, 1821-1925; Series IV; 1.5; (4 boxes)
  Series IV, Family Correspondence, housed in Boxes 14-17, contains correspondence between the Francis A. Thornton family, the George Foster Emmons Family, and other relations of the two families. The original arrangement and titles of the letterbooks have been preserved. Letters to George Thornton Emmons from colleagues, navy officers, and friends are at the end of the series.
  - 1821-5- LETTERS OF F. A. THORNTON, U.S. NAVY
    - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 246)
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 247-49)
    - Letters, 1821-30 (Box 14, Folder 250-52)
    - Letters, 1833-45 (Box 14, Folder 253-58)
    - Letters, 1849 (Box 14, Folder 259)
    - Letters, 1851-52 (Box 14, Folder 260-61)
    - Letters, 1880 (Box 14, Folder 262)
  - 1828-58 PERSONAL LETTERS THORNTON & EMMONS FAMILY
    - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 263)
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 264-66)
    - Letters, 1828-34 (Box 14, Folder 267)
    - Letters, 1843-46 (Box 14, Folder 268-71)
    - Letters, 1847-57 (Box 15, Folder 272-85)
    - Letters and index, 1858, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 286)
  - 1860-67 LETTERS, G.F.-A. EMMONS, DURING REBELLION
    - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 287)
    - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 288-90)
    - Letters, 1860-61 (Box 15, Folder 291-93)
    - [Reports on U.S. Navy], n.d. (Box 15, Folder 294)
    - Letters, 1862-65 (Box 16, Folder 295-305)
  - 1874-1905 OFFICIAL LETTERS TO GEORGE T. EMMONS
    - Letters, 1874-78 (Box 16, Folder 306)
    - Letters, 1880-88 (Box 16, Folder 307-08)
    - Letters, 1891-99 (Box 16, Folder 309-10)
    - Letters, 1900-05 (Box 16, Folder 311-12)
    - Letters, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 313)
  - 1887-1925 PERSONAL-OFFICIAL TO GEORGE T. EMMONS
    - Letters, 1887, 1889 (Box 16, Folder 314)
    - Letters, 1890-96 (Box 16, Folder 315)
    - Letters, 1897-98 (Box 17, Folder 316)
    - Letters, 1900-01 (Box 17, Folder 317)
    - Letters, court papers, and newspaper clippings, 1902 (Box 17, Folder 318-19)
    - Letters, 1903-10 (Box 17, Folder 320-22)
    - Letters, 1914-25 (Box 17, Folder 323)
    - Letters, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 324)
- Naval Service Material, 1818-1901; Series V; 2; (5 boxes)
  Series V, Naval Service Material, housed in Boxes 18-22, is divided into Ship Journals (Logbooks) and Letterbooks, which chronicles navy cruises, and Orders and Reports, which contains materials gathered by George Foster and George Thornton Emmons that document naval affairs. The material is arranged in rough chronological order.
  - SHIP JOURNALS (LOGBOOKS) AND LETTERBOOKS
    - George Foster Emmons
      - Journal of a Cruise on the frigate Brandywine, 1830-33 (Box 18, Folder 325)
      - Brandywine, vol. 1: detached material, 1831-32 (Box 18, Folder 326-28)
      - Journal of Homebound Cruise the frigate Brandywine, and Exploration Cruises in South America, 1833-38 (Box 18, Folder 329)
      - [Journals of Cruise on the sloop of war Peacock ], 1838-42
        See: Manuscript 166, Yale Collection of Western Americana
      - Private Journal of a Cruise in the sloop of war Boston, 1843-46 (Box 18, Folder 330)
      - Boston: detached material, 1833-38 (Box 18, Folder 331)
      - Boston: detached material, 1833-38 (Box 19, Folder 332-35)
      - Journal of a Cruise in the frigate Savannah, 1853-56 (Box 19, Folder 336)
      - Savannah: detached material, 1853-56 (Box 19, Folder 337-44)
      - Letterbook of U.S.S. Savannah
        - Dealer's listing of material, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 345)
        - Letterbook, 1856-1858 (Box 19, Folder 346)
        - Detached material, 1856, 1859, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 347-48)
      - Letterbook of U.S.S. Lackawanna, 1865 (Box 20, Folder 349)
      - Lackawanna: detached material, 1865, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 350-52)
      - Letterbook of U.S.S. Ossipee
        - Cover of letterbook, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 353-54)
        - Letterbook pages, 1866-69 (Box 20, Folder 355-66)
        - Detached material: two maps of Alaskan coast
          See: Oversize, Box 31, folder 548
          Related Materials
          See: Oversize, 33 (Broadside)
    - George Thornton Emmons
      - Cruise of the U.S.S. Pinta, Inland Passage, Alaskan Waters, 1883-91 (Box 20, Folder 367)
  - ORDERS AND REPORTS
    - George Foster Emmons
      - Circulars and Orders
        - Cover of the letterbook, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 368-69)
        - Letterbook pages, 1840-66 (Box 21, Folder 370-77)
      - Reports on Navy Vessels, Prizes, 1860-76 (Box 21, Folder 378)
      - Navy Vessels: detached material, p. 5-121, 1860-76 (Box 21, Folder 379-84)
      - Navy Vessels: detached material, p. 191-end, 1860-76 (Box 22, Folder 385-87)
      - Reports from the Navy Yard, Philadelphia, 1870-72 (Box 22, Folder 388)
      - Navy Yard: detached material, 1870 Dec (Box 22, Folder 389)
    - George Thornton Emmons
      - Accounts of the Government of the District of Alaska, 1888-1901 (Box 22, Folder 390)
    - Navy Regulations
      - Rules, Regulations, and Instructions, for the Naval Service of the United States, 1818 (Box 22, Folder 391)
      - Rules of the Navy Department, Regulating the Civil Administration of the Navy of the United States, 1832 (Box 22, Folder 392)
- Alaskan Papers of George T. Emmons, 1872-1925; Series VI; 1.5; (5 boxes)
  Series VI, Alaskan Papers of George T. Emmons, housed in Boxes 23-27, contains two scrapbooks representing Emmons's research; photographs documenting Alaskan Indians; subject files, divided into general files arranged alphabetically and files on the Tlingit qwans and families; and printed works arranged chronologically.
  - SCRAPBOOKS
    - "Alaska Work, Writings, Letters and Notes"
      - Scrapbook
        See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 546
      - Material detached from scrapbook, 1869-1930 (Box 23, Folder 393-407)
    - "Conditions and Needs of the Natives of Alaska"
      - Scrapbook, 1896-1905, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 408)
      - Material detached from scrapbook, 1872-1906, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 409-21)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    See also: Box 24, folder 437
    - Tlingit Indians, 1885-1902, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 422)
    - Tlingit artifacts, 1902, 1905, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 423-24)
    - Chilkat blankets, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 425-27)
    - Women weaving Chilkat blankets, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 428-29)
    - Tlingit Indian designs on wood (Box 23, Folder 430-31)
    - Alaska, 1888, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 432)
    - British Columbia, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 433)
    - Officers of the H.M.S. Pheasant, 1896 (Box 23, Folder 434)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 435)
  - SUBJECT FILES
    - General
      - Age (Box 24, Folder 436)
      - Alaskan stone boundary markers, 1902 (Box 24, Folder 437)
      - Armor and weapons (Box 24, Folder 438)
      - Arts and industry, 1885, 1888, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 439)
      - "Chapter IV: Villages, houses...", 1888, 1902, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 440)
      - "Chapter V: Domestic life", 1900, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 441-44)
      - "Chapter V: The People", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 445)
      - "Chapter IX: War and Peace" (Box 24, Folder 446)
      - Chieftanship, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 447)
      - Childbirth, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 448)
      - Children's songs, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 449)
      - Confinement of young women, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 450)
      - Dances, feasts, potlatches, 1888-1901, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 451-52)
      - Death customs, 1882, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 453)
      - Division of property, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 454)
      - Dogs, 1900, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 455)
      - Family emblems or totems, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 456)
      - Family relationships, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 457)
      - Fishing and hunting (Box 24, Folder 458)
      - Gambling, 1902, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 459)
      - Indemnity (Box 25, Folder 460)
      - "The Legend of the [Tahlka]" (Box 25, Folder 461)
      - Marriage, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 462)
      - Names and naming (Box 25, Folder 463)
      - Packing and trading (Box 25, Folder 464)
      - Peace customs and dance, 1890-91, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 465-66)
      - Salmon, 1891, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 467)
      - Seasons, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 468)
      - Shamanism, 1888, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 469-72)
      - "Slate Mirrors of the Tsimshian", 1920, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 473)
      - Slaves, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 474)
      - Spirits, 1882, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 475)
      - Tobacco cultivation and snuff making (Box 25, Folder 476)
      - War customs, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 477-78)
      - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 479)
    - Tlingit Qwans
      - List of Tlingit Qwans, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 480)
      - Auk Qwan, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 481)
      - Chilkat Qwan, 1891, 1911, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 482)
      - Gunahho Qwan, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 483)
      - Hennek Qwan, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 484)
      - Hoolzak Tai Qwan, 1907, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 485)
      - Hoonah Kow Qwan, 1882, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 486)
      - Kehk Qwan, ca. 1890, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 488)
      - Klawak Qwan, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 489)
      - Kuyu Qwan, ca. 1890, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 490)
      - Sitka Qwan, ca. 1890, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 491)
      - Sonnak Qwan, ca. 1880, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 492)
      - Stickheen, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 493)
      - Sum Dum Qwan, ca. 1890, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 494)
      - Taku Qwan, ca. 1889, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 495)
      - Thlarharyeet Qwan, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 496)
      - Tonta Qwan, ca. 1890, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 497)
      - Miscellaneous Qwan, 1891-1916, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 498)
      - List of Raven and Wolf families (Box 26, Folder 499)
      - Raven Families, 1911, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 500)
      - Wolf Families, 1911, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 501)
      - Miscellaneous families, 1911, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 502)
  - WRITINGS
    - "The Basketry of the Tlingit," Memoirs of the American Museum of Natural History. vol. III
      See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 547
    - Basketry: detached material, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 503)
    - Extract from the New York Times, "Details of Lieutenant George T. Emmons' Discoveries Sustaining the United States Contention," in Alaska Boundary. Various Documents Bearing on the Question of the Alaska Boundary, 1903 (Box 26, Folder 504)
    - Extract: detached material, 1903-04 (Box 26, Folder 505-06)
    - "The Chilkat Blanket," Memoirs of the American Museum of Natural History. vol. III.
      See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 547a
    - Chilkat Blanket: detached material, 1908, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 506a-06b)
    - "Petroglyphs in Southeastern Alaska," American Anthropologist. vol. 10, no. 2. (reprint), 1908 (Box 26, Folder 507)
    - [Review of]"The Chilkat Blanket," American Anthropologist. vol. 10, no. 2. (reprint), 1908 (Box 26, Folder 508)
    - "The Use of the Chilcat Blanket," The American Museum Journal. vol. VIII, no. 5., 1908 May (Box 26, Folder 509)
    - "The Potlatch of the North Pacific Coast," The American Museum Journal. vol. X, no. 8., 1910 Dec (Box 26, Folder 510)
    - "Native Account of the Meeting Between La Perouse and the Tlingit," American Anthropologist. vol. XIII, no. 2. (reprint), 1911 (Box 26, Folder 511)
    - "The Tahltan Indians," University of Pennsylvanis. The Museum Publications. vol. IV, no.1: copy with material inserted, 1911 (Box 26, Folder 512)
    - Tahltan Indians: detached material, 1909, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 513-16)
    - "The Kitselas of British Columbia," American Anthropologist. vol. XIV, no. 3. (reprint), 1912 (Box 26, Folder 517)
    - "Some Kitksan Totem Poles," The American Museum Journal. vol. XIII, no. 8., 1913 Dec (Box 26, Folder 518)
    - "Portraiture Among North Pacific Coast Tribes," American Anthropologist. vol. 16, no. 1. (reprint), 1914 (Box 27, Folder 519)
    - "Tsimshian Stories in Carved Wood," The American Museum Journal. vol. XV, no. 7., 1915 Nov (Box 27, Folder 520)
    - "Slate Mirrors of the Tsimshian," Indian Notes and Monographs., 1921 (Box 27, Folder 521)
    - "Jade in British Columbia and Alaska, and its Use by the Natives," Indian Notes and Monographs., 1923 (Box 27, Folder 522)
    - "The Kitikshan and their Totem Poles," Natural History. vol. XXV, no. 1, 1925 Jan-Feb (Box 27, Folder 523)
- Family Papers, 1830-86; Series VII; 0.5; (1 box)
  Series VII, Family Papers, housed in Box 28, contains scrapbooks and artwork by George Foster Emmons, George Thornton Emmons, and Kittie Emmons.
  - GEORGE FOSTER EMMONS
    - Scrapbook regarding naval court martial on U.S.S. North Carolina, of Wilkes and others, 1842
      See: Manuscript 169, Yale Collection of Western Americana
    - Civil War scrapbook of newspaper clippings
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 543
    - Civil War scrapbook: detached material, 1861-63 (Box 28, Folder 524-30)
    - Seamanship of Robert K. Wyman, by George Foster Emmons, [pre-1835] (Box 28, Folder 531)
    - Dealer's list of drawings, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 532)
    - Drawings while on the Brandywine: pencil sketches, 1830-33 (Box 28, Folder 533-35)
    - Scrapbook and drawings: pencil sketches, black-white and hand-colored prints, 1830-36, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 536)
    - Sketchbooks of drawings while on South Seas Surveying and Exploring Expedition on the sloop of war Peacock: two sketchbooks, pencil drawings
    - Invitations, 1869-73 (Box 28, Folder 537)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1835-72, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 538)
  - GEORGE THORNTON EMMONS
    - Christmas pamphlet: scenes of Alaska, oil paint, 1886 (Box 28, Folder 539)
    - Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition: two diplomas for "Valuable Services Rendered" and "Grand Prize for Exhibit", 1909
    - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 540)
  - KITTIE M. EMMONS
    - "Old Russian Blockhouse at entrance of Indian Village, Sitka, Alaska:" watercolor, 1886 (Box 28, Folder 541)
- Oversize, 3.75; (3 boxes)
  Oversize material contains oversize material from Series I, II, IV, VI, and VII, in a parallel arrangement.
  - G. F. EMMONS OFFICIAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - 1872 [Official]
      - [empty folder] (Box 29, Folder 542)
  - FAMILY PAPERS
    - George Foster Emmons
      - Civil War scrapbook of newspaper clippings, 1861-63 (Box 29, Folder 543)
  - G. F. EMMONS PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - 1863-65 Official & Personal, Civil War
      - Letters, 1864 Mar-Apr (Box 30, Folder 544)
  - ADDITIONAL CORRESPONDENCE, G. F. EMMONS
    - 1841-73 Letters
      - "South Fork of the American River, California:" map, 1848 Jul 20 (Box 30, Folder 545)
  - ALASKAN PAPERS OF GEORGE T. EMMONS
    - Scrapbooks
      - "Alaska Work, Writings, Letters and Notes"
        - Scrapbook, 1882-1906 (Box 30, Folder 546)
  - WRITINGS
    - "The Basketry of the Tlingit," Memoirs of the American Museum of Natural History. vol. III, 1903 Jul (Box 30, Folder 547)
    - "The Chilkat Blanket," Memoirs of the American Museum of Natural History. vol. III., 1907 Dec (Box 30, Folder 547a)
  - NAVAL SERVICE MATERIAL
    - Ship Journals and Letterbooks
      - George Foster Emmons
        - Letterbook of the U.S.S. Ossipee. Detached material: map of the Alaskan coast, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 548)
          No Subnote Content
  - FAMILY PAPERS
    - George Thornton Emmons
      - Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition: two diplomas for "Valuable Services Rendered" and "Grand Prize for Exhibit", 1909 (Box 31, Folder 549)
  - OTHER OVERSIZE PAPERS
    - G. F. EMMONS OFFICIAL CORRESPONDENCE
      - 1872 [Official]
        - Sunday Dispatch: Philadelphia newspaper, vol. XXVIII, no. 42, 1872 January 23 (Box 33 (Broadside))
    - NAVAL SERVICE MATERIAL
      - Ship Journals and Letterbooks
        - George Foster Emmons